PAULO BRUNO SERAFIM

Deep Reinforcement Learning Researcher | Software Developer

I like to find creative solutions for challenging problems, to work on novel solutions to relevant and nontrivial matters. Through my experience on varied projects, I have learned not only to love problem-solving but also to share discoveries through writing.

SKILLS

C/C++ 9 years

Data-Oriented and Object-Oriented C/C++

Reinforcement Learning 6 years Deep Q-Networks and Policy Gradients

Computer Graphics 6 years

CG, 3D Printing, Computational Geometry, and Geometric Modelling in OpenGL and Qt

Python 5 years

ML projects with Numpy, Scikit and Matplotlib

Deep Learning 5 years

TensorFlow and Keras in Python

Image Processing and 3 years Computer Vision

OpenCV, Image Segmentation, and OCR

Assembly 1 year

Z80 processor (GBASM)

LANGUAGES

Native Speaker

Full Professional Proficiency

FR Limited Professional Proficiency

SOCIAL

paulobruno.github.io

in linkedin.com/in/pbserafim

github.com/paulobruno

R⁶ researchgate.net/profile/Paulo-Serafim

CV lattes.cnpq.br/7877766764101416

CONTACT

2 1100 Benjamim Brasil, Fortaleza, Brazil

+55 85 999972923

pbrunosousa@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Deep RL Researcher

Apr. 2018 - Present

CRAb - Computer Graphics, Virtual Reality and Animation

Deep Reinforcement Learning (DRL) researcher, working with autonomous game agents using TensorFlow and the environments ViZDoom, OpenAl Gym, and Unity ML-Agents. Co-advisor of one BSc, two MSc, and one PhD candidate students. Currently working on analysis of agent's performance under different views of the same scenario by using model interpretability methods.

Senior Data Scientist

May 2021 - Mar. 2022

Instituto Atlântico

Tech Lead of the Data Science branch of an R&D project for Dell EMC. Working with anomaly detection using unsupervised learning methods, classification using supervised learning methods, and development of Business Intelligence dashboards to assist tactical and operational decision making.

Computer Vision Engineer

Sept. 2020 - Apr. 2021

Instituto Atlântico

Worked on an R&D Computer Vision project for HP Inc. applying Deep Learning to the problems of human segmentation and image matting using TensorFlow. Worked on OCR methods applied to printed text documents. Developed a synthetic document generator using OpenCV. Co-leader of the Cognitive Computing study group, focused on CV, Image Processing, and Reinforcement Learning.

Computer Graphics Engineer Feb. 2019 - Aug. 2020

Instituto Atlântico

Worked on R&D projects for HP Labs on 3D printing, applying computer graphics methods using only C/C++ standard libraries. Developed a new way to build voxelized support structures, which generated a patent application (2019). Worked on improvements of Genetic Algorithm heuristics applied to a Bin Packing Problem (2020).

Software Developer

May 2018 - Feb. 2019

GREat - ASTEF

Developed solutions for fingerprint minutiae extraction and matching focused on high-performance, using OpenCV in C++. Implemented a data-oriented C++ version of SourceAFIS, reducing runtime in about 90%. Created a side project using Convolutional Neural Networks for fingerprint ROI segmentation. Worked on a Transfer Learning solution to enhance fingerprint images. Helped the team with singular point detection using YOLOv4.

EDUCATION

STUDENTS (CO-ADVISOR)

MSc - Computer Science	Mar. 2016 – Apr. 2018	Halisson Rodrigo	PhD	2020 – Present
Advisor: Dr. Joaquim Bento Cavalcante Neto Co-Advisors: Dr. Creto Augusto Vidal and Dr. Yuri Lenon Nogueira Thesis: Evaluating competition in training of Deep Reinforcement Learning agents in First-Person Shooter games (in Portuguese) Research on multi-agent competitive applications of Deep Q- Networks using the environment ViZDoom and TensorFlow.		Alexandre Magno	BSc/MSc	2019 – Present
		Rômulo Férrer Filho	BSc/MSc	2019 – Present
		Hyuan Farrapo	BSc	2020 - 2022
		Anderson Oliveira	BSc/MSc	2017 – 2020
BSc – Computer Science Federal University of Ceará (UFC) – Magna	Jan. 2013 – Dec. 2015 Cum Laude degree	Matheus Cordeiro	BSc	2017 - 2019
Worked on hair animation projects u	ng mass-spring systems and on Neuroevolution for	Eduardo Melo	BSc	2015 – 2017
autonomous game agents (2014-2015).		Gabriel Costa	BSc	2015 – 2017
PUBLICATIONS				
Assessing the Robustness of Deep Q-Network Agents to Changes on Game Object Textures XX Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames)				Oct. 2021
Gym Hero: A Research Environment for Reinforcement Learning Agents in Rhythm Games XX Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames)				Oct. 2021
Robust Fingerprint Singular Point Detection using a Single-Stage CNN for Object Detection 28th International Conference on Systems, Signals, and Image Processing (IWSSIP)				June 2021
Investigating Deep Q-Network Agent Sensibility to Texture Changes on FPS Games XIX Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames)				Nov. 2020
Deep Reinforcement Learning em Ambientes Virtuais (in Portuguese) XXII Symposium on Virtual and Augmented Reality (SVR) - Pre-Symposium Book				Nov. 2020
Autonomous Foraging with SARSA-based Deep Reinforcement Learning XXII Symposium on Virtual and Augmented Reality (SVR)				Nov. 2020
Simplificando o Balanceamento de Atributos em RPGs Eletrônicos (in Portuguese) XIX Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames)				Nov. 2020
A Novel Approach for Automatic Enhancement of Fingerprint Images via Deep Transfer Learning 2020 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)				July 2020
A Minimal Training Strategy to Play Flappy Bird Indefinitely with NEAT 18th Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames)				Oct. 2019
A Method based on Convolutional Neural Networks for Fingerprint Segmentation 2019 International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN)				July 2019
Evaluating Competition in Training of Deep Reinforcement Learning Agents in First-Person Shooter Games 17th Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames)				s Oct. 2018
On the Development of an Autonomous Agent for a 3D First-Person Shooter Game Using Deep				Nov. 2017
Reinforcement Learning 16th Brazilian Symposium on Computer Games and Digital Entertainment (SBGames)				
Towards Playing a 3D First-Person Shooter Game Using a Classification Deep Neural Network Architecture 19th Symposium on Virtual and Augmented Reality (SVR 2017)				e Nov. 2017

REFERENCES

Dr. Joaquim Cavalcante Neto

BSc and MSc Advisor Federal University of Ceará (UFC) Block 910 – Pici Campus 60455-760 Fortaleza, Ceará, Brazil +5585999971297 joaquimb@dc.ufc.br

Dr. Creto Augusto Vidal

BSc and MSc Co-Advisor Federal University of Ceará (UFC) Block 910 – Pici Campus 60455-760 Fortaleza, Ceará, Brazil +5585996627603 cvidal@dc.ufc.br

Romildo Ferreira Lima

Former Employer Instituto Atlântico Washington Soares Avenue, 909 60811-341 Fortaleza, Ceará, Brazil +5585996284902 romildo_lima@atlantico.com.br